MANASH JYOTI BARUAH

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mangaldai, Assam, India

+91 8638043872

manashjbwork@gmail.com

https://devmj.netlify.app



Software Developer with more than 1.5+ years of experience and a passion for web application development. Skilled in conceptualizing, designing, development, and deploying web applications. Dedicated to driving innovation with the ability to follow industry and technological trends.

EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (Aug 2021-Present)

Laitkor Consultancy Pvt. Ltd

- Worked on CI/CD using AWS services using CDK typescript.
- Worked on projects using AWS Lambda, Cognito, S3,Ecs
- Built a Complete Serverless Call Centre using AWS Connect, AWS Lambda, S3 in JavaScript.
- Created serverless UI for .ini file management with ReactJs, AWS S3 and JavaScript.
- Worked on front-end part of Web application using VueJs and ReactJs.
- Worked on SaaS product development using AWS.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER Intern (Jan 2021-Jun 2021)

Parlay Construction pvt ltd.

- Worked on Real estate Website Building with custom CMS.
- Develop and maintain apis.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (MCA)

Assam Don Bosco University, Azara, Guwahati(2019-2021) CGPA: 8.1

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (BCA)

Pandu College, Guwahati, (2016-2019) CGPA: 7.2

LATEST PROJECTS

ECOMMERCE WEBSITE

- Front-end: ReactJs
- Back-end: NodeJs, ExpressJs, REST api, MongoDB
- GitHub Link: https://github.com/ManashJBofficial/e-shop https://easykart.onrender.com

ANDROID MOVIE APP

- Stack: React, React Native, Expo, TMDB api, other Movie
- GitHub Link: https://github.com/ManashJBofficial/ movieapp

SKILLS

AWS Services:

CodePipeline,CodeBuild,Lambda, Amplify, Cognito, S3, RDS-Aurora, MySQL, Api Gateway, Route53,ECS

Web Dev Languages & Frameworks:

HTML, Css/Sassnner, Bootstrap, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, VueJs (Beginner)

Programming Language:

Javascript

Database:

MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB

Design Tools:

Adobe XD

Container:

Docker (Beginner)

Operating System:

Windows, Linux

Other skills:

Git, Bash, Ms-Office

Mobile App Development:

React Native (Beginner)

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Desire to Learn new things
- Dedicated Team-member
- Confident
- Responsibility

LANGUAGES

Assamese • Hindi • English

SOCIAL LINKS



https://www.linkedin.com/in/manashjb



https://github.com/ManashJBofficial